Catholics Against Capital Punishment; Records apap321
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records
1972-2010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap321
0.80 cubic ft.
The Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records is a small collection that contains several articles, statements, and pamphlets making a case against the death penalty from a Catholic standpoint.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Frank McNeirney donated the Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records in 2010 to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
Francis (Frank) McNeirney and his wife Ellen founded Catholics Against Capital Punishment (CACP) in 1992 in Bethesda, Maryland. The organization's goal was to take a public pro-life stance against the death penalty using Catholicism as a basis for its views, and encourage others with similar mind-sets to support or join the cause. In late 2011 founder Frank McNeirney passed away, and his wife decided to retire from the organization. She passed the organization's website domain on to a sister organization, Catholic Mobilizing Network, for its use, so that supporters of CACP could continue their outreach.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers related to the Catholics Against Capital Punishment (CACP) cause, most notably articles and statements regarding the death penalty from a Catholic perspective. Some booklets and pamphlets from conferences and other organizations are included as well. A large part of the collection consists of articles and statements organized by the state of origin. The District of Columbia is included along with 44 states; Delaware, Hawaii, Oklahoma, Tennessee, Vermont, and Wyoming are missing. There are several official statements released or sanctioned by the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops, referred to as U.S.C.C.B. for convenience. One compact disk is included in the collection that accompanies the booklet Death Penalty Resources for Communities of Faith.
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred one monograph: Beyond the Death Penalty written by Joe Holland and D. Michael McCarron to the book division of Special Collections. This was cataloged and included in the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Death Penalty; Capital punishment--Religious aspects--Baptists, [Catholic Church, etc.]; Articles; Pamphlets; Catholics Against Capital Punishment; Catholic Church. United States Conference of Catholic Bishops
- Articles and Statements-Alabama, 1983 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 1)
- Articles and Statements-Alaska, 1985 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 2)
- Articles and Statements-Arizona, 2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 3)
- Articles and Statements-Arkansas, 1995 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 4)
- Articles and Statements-California, 1985; 1992-1993; 1999; Undated (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 5)
- Articles and Statements-Colorado, 1994; 1997; 2002; 2005; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 6)
- Articles and Statements-Connecticut, 1990; 1998-1999; 2005; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 7)
- Articles and Statements-District of Columbia, 1992 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 8)
- Articles and Statements-Florida, 1972-1979; 1983-1984; 1990-1997; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 9)
- Articles and Statements-Georgia, 1992; 2008 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 10)
- Articles and Statements-Idaho, 1994 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 11)
- Articles and Statements-Illinois, 1983; 1988; 1994-1996; 1998-1999; 2002 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 12)
- Articles and Statements-Indiana, 1986; 1994; 1996; 1998-1999; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 13)
- Articles and Statements-Iowa, 1998 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 14)
- Articles and Statements-Kansas, 1994; 1998; 2002; 2009-2010 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 15)
- Articles and Statements-Kentucky, 1984; 1996; 2007; Undated (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 16)
- Articles and Statements-Louisiana, 1992; 1994; 1996 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 17)
- Articles and Statements-Maine, 1996; Undated (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 18)
- Articles and Statements-Maryland, 1993; 1996-1998; 2005; 2008-2009; Undated (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 19)
- Articles and Statements-Massachusetts, 1997; 1999; 2001; 2004; 2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 20)
- Articles and Statements-Michigan, 1985-1986; 1993; 1999 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 21)
- Articles and Statements-Minnesota, 1993; 2003-2004 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 22)
- Articles and Statements-Mississippi, 1987 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 23)
- Articles and Statements-Missouri, 1994; 2006; 2010 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 24)
- Articles and Statements-Montana, 1995; 2006-2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 25)
- Articles and Statements-Nebraska, 1994; 1996; 2010; Undated (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 26)
- Articles and Statements-Nevada, 1996; 1998 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 27)
- Articles and Statements-New Hampshire, 2007-2010 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 28)
- Articles and Statements-New Jersey, 1989; 1993; 1996-1999; 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 29)
- Articles and Statements-New Mexico, 1996; 1998-1999; 2000; 2010 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 30)
- Articles and Statements-New York, 1994-1996; 1999; 2002-2003; 2005; 2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 31)
- Articles and Statements-North Carolina, 2005 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 32)
- Articles and Statements-North Dakota, 1995 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 33)
- Articles and Statements-Ohio, 1987; 1996; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 34)
- Articles and Statements-Oregon, 1996; 2009 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 35)
- Articles and Statements-Pennsylvania, 1989; 1995-1996; 2000-2001; 2007 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 36)
- Articles and Statements-Rhode Island, 1994 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 37)
- Articles and Statements-South Carolina, 1992; 1998 (Box 1 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 38)
- Articles and Statements-South Dakota, 2007 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 1)
- Articles and Statements-Texas, 1979; 1984-1985; 1992-1999; 2000-2008 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 2)
- Articles and Statements-Utah, 2010 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 3)
- Articles and Statements-Virginia, 1988; 1993; 2001; 2007; 2009 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 4)
- Articles and Statements-Washington State, 1992; 1998; 2007; 2009 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 5)
- Articles and Statements-West Virginia, 1980; 1986 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 6)
- Articles and Statements-Wisconsin, 1987; 1993; 1995 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 7)
- General Pamphlets, Articles, and Statements Regarding Catholic Views on the Death Penalty, 1992-1995; 1997-1998; 2000-2005; Undated (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 8)
- Testimony and Letters to the U.S. Senate, House of Representatives, and the Supreme Court issued with the support of the U.S.C.C.B., 1989; 1994; 2001 (Box 2 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 9)
- U.S.C.C.B. Official Statements, 1978; 1980; 1984-1990; 2000-2005 (Box 3 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 1)
- Vatican Officials' Statements, 1991; 1996-1999; 2001; 2005-2010 (Box 3 (Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records ), Folder 2)